Hi, in the previous words and we compare it different ways to work with AI.
Now we will use mixed approach where we will have one, design and additional details.
To get the best result, this means we'll provide both the UI's screenshot and the required
functionality to the console AI and then we'll add him to build a clear plan before writing
any code.
It will help us to build faster while still keeping the project clean and correct because
we'll first review the plan and then we will apply it.
Okay, let me now explain why the plan is better.
Many developers jam into coding too early.
Without the plan, the application can become messy, hard to maintain and even the
required full writes because mass and planned and it will go randomly in most of the cases.
But a short planning step helps the AI understand the full feature and keeps the code
organized from the very beginning.
So using the console planning mode, so we will use the console plan mode, let me first show
you.
I will open the secondary bar and this is a plan mode we will use.
So it will help break the project into clear steps into tasks so AI can suggest file and
further structure.
You can describe what each component will do.
You can ask for some follow-up questions before start to implement the plan.
So we can write it, we can change anything we want.
And of course, you will ask us to review and then confirm the creation, the application.
So before you start to write in a prompt and use the plan, I suggest you open a folder
where you will create your project.
I will open my projects folder, I will sort of you will create in this folder, folder
with the application, wherever you will work.
Let's see, let's again show the sidebar, I will switch to plan mode and I prepare it prompt.
Let me type the prompt right here and before we go through the prompt, let me explain
you what it will do.
So we will give a clear description, provide some screenshot, what up you want, technical
stack, stack some UI details, we will ask for the first generator plan step by step, then
we can read our plan, we can review it carefully, if need adjust something, then we can
approve it and ask for sort of the build it for us and then we'll sort of go do task
by task, the building an application and after that we can review all the changes.
So let's go through the prompt, I ask for sort to create a step by step when the build
this application from the screenshot using with React and TypeScript.
I also need to upload the screenshot, so this is the screenshot of currency converter, I
saw it at the internet, it has among fields currency from and to the shows exchange rate
and have the button to calculate the conversion.
So I go apply it, attach it as a file, then I describe the functionality, then application
must convert and enter the amount from one currency to another, we will use some time
data for it, for the beginning, just a quick rebuild it.
So we also will swap in between currencies and we also show the result in expected format,
so we tell a sort of what format is expected for us, we also ask keep simple CSS, this
reflects and selects and also centers the card play out, so we can ask for sort to build
the plan.
Okay, it may take a few minutes to build the plan, maybe I think even faster about the
minute, oh, it first need to see what we want, you analyze it, maybe sort of something
at the internet.
Okay, but we already have, he's wrapped in a plan, we have a title, we have sections, every
section needs the steps, our plan, at the bottom you will have to do of the steps, so the
first step is the project setup, he will create with project with the action tab script,
this is a common hero use to create this template and also he will open the project, install
all dependencies and run it, he also will clean up the boilerplate, boilerplate code from
a main in application, some code we won't use just like this plays a React template, and
then he'll add some global styles inside index dot CSS, okay, that's good, then he suggests
the file structure for our application, so we will have the common structure of as with
applications has, we will have the currency select, the amount input component, the result
component, the swap button, we'll have the currencies where we will have, I suppose my
visit list of the currencies, and in the data we will have our market rates, yes, and
of course the index dot CSS, we'll have some styles, then here we will have some data
and utilities, he'll explain the structure, how he will store the currencies, so every
currency have called name and flag, okay, that's fine, we'll have more great, okay, that's
also great, there is a function to get the rate and there is a function to convert, it's
very smart, so if in your plan it doesn't look so the way it looks for me, don't worry
because AI is generative, it can generate the same code example for everyone, might it
because I've been using cursor before, it know my preferences and it build it more architecture
approach and build it more as I expect, yes, but in the next lessons on considerations
we will improve it, improve the code, improve the structure, so you can do the same, so don't
worry, you'll result in your plan, you will differently for sure, so then we have a list
of components, we already discussed them, we have the apology, so we do store states for
a amount, store the components, it's a two currency, there is a result, it also needed,
you'll have some methods and there's a conversion and swap, some styling, accessibility,
okay, even think about it, it's great, some manual test cases, so I didn't ask to add
this cases but, okay, and we have a to-dos, so all steps we get go through before, okay,
this is our plan, I see in the next lesson where we will build an application with this
plan and I hope it will be useful for you.